VISHAL MADHAV

FRONT-END DEVELOPER



201-637-0929 W vmadhav33@gmail.com (h) https://www.linkedin.com/in/vishal-madhav/ https://github.com/vm0303



PROFILE

A front-end developer interested in UI/UX design, and various front-end applications / services. An eager learner with good critical-thinking and problem-solving skills. An expert in various languages and frameworks, with a penchant to learn and grow in the industry.

PROJECTS

Angular Music, Front-End Web Application $\ \ \, \Box$ A web application that plays royalty-free music from various artists including famous American composer, Kevin MacLeod. Used Angular, Howler.js, & JavaScript.

2048 Game. Front-End Web Application

A single-player sliding block puzzle game where the objective is to slide numbered tiles on a grid to combine them in order to create a tile with the number 2048. Used Vue & Firestore from Google Firebase.

Hangman Game, Front-End Web Application ☐

A guessing word game where the goal is to guess a word based on what letters it contains. Each wrong guess a player makes brings them one step closer to losing. Used simple HTML, CSS, & JavaScript.

React Puzzles, Front-End Web Application □

A web application where two popular puzzles that are most commonly seen in the Computer Science industry were implemented. Used React.

CodeFlower, Full-Stack Web Application □

A website that helps teach middle school and high school students the fundamental basics of Python programming, which can help be a learning tool for people who want to pursue Computer Science in the future. Used Python, HTML, CSS, MySQL, and JavaScript.

CodeFlower Info, Front-End Web Application □

A supporting website that goes into detail about the full-stack web application that me and my team did for the Capstone project in college. Used simple HTML, CSS, & JavaScript.

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

HTML, CSS, Python, Java, JavaScript, TypeScript

FRAMEWORKS & LIBRARIES

React, Vue, Angular, Bootstrap, Material UI, Tailwind CSS

DATABASES

MySQL

MISC

GitHub, GitHub Pages, Firebase, Vercel, Adobe XD

INTER-PERSONAL

Collaborative Leadership, People-Oriented, Interpersonal Communication, Positive Attitude, Teamwork

EXPERIENCE

Mentee

Microsoft

JULY 2021 - AUGUST 2021

- Mentored by Microsoft executives and senior employees located in New York City and at the Redmond, Washington headquarters.
- Worked on a team with 3 other mentees to produce a Hackathon project to revolutionize the way we throw our trash or recyclable items in public areas with a smart trash can.
- · Attended sessions to learn about Microsoft's products, culture, and operations.
- Shadowed a Microsoft Account Manager and learned about technical escalations and interacting with executive-level customers
- Met with product group employees from Cortana, HoloLens, Xbox, and Microsoft 365 Security to learn about their solutions, and their goals and incentives in the future.

Intern

National Thermal Power Corporation (N.T.P.C) JULY 2019 - AUGUST 2019

- Worked and interacted on various projects with engineers in the power plant and learned about the daily activities they do to keep the power plant secure.
- Understood how the electric grid in the power plant helps power the southern states of the country like Karnataka, Andhra Pradesh, Tamil Nadu, Kerala, and more.

EDUCATION

B.S. Pennsylvania State University - Harrisburg 2018 - 2022

Computer Science

Secondary Education, John P. Stevens High School 2014 - 2018

LANGUAGES

English



Telugu